<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Guoqing Geng</title>
    <link>https://hellokangning.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Guoqing Geng</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 May 2017 21:49:20 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://hellokangning.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://hellokangning.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 May 2017 21:49:20 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hellokangning.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>My name is Guoqing Geng. I was born and raised in China(🇨🇳), currently work as a Big Data Engineer with technology stack including but not limited to:
 HBase Elasticsearch Spark  Programming Languages I usually cope with cover:
 C++ Python Scala  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unpacking in Python</title>
      <link>https://hellokangning.github.io/post/python-unpacking/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Aug 2018 20:02:15 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hellokangning.github.io/post/python-unpacking/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Python provides many friendly advanced API for programmer, one of which is unpacking. By unpacking, it means getting all the elements from a container. A simplest case in the below demostrates assigns the two items in tuple to variables.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; a, b = (1,2)
&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; a
1
&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; b
2
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Besides tuple, every iterative object can support unpacking, such as list, dictionary, set, string, generator etc. Let&amp;rsquo;s traverse them one by one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Quick Retrospect of Design Pattern</title>
      <link>https://hellokangning.github.io/post/retrospect-design-pattern/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Aug 2018 15:24:26 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hellokangning.github.io/post/retrospect-design-pattern/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This post summarizes some design patterns I used in daily work or learnt from books.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hellokangning.github.io/images/design-pattern-overview.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Linux: Principles, Manual and Programming</title>
      <link>https://hellokangning.github.io/post/linux-principle-manual-programming/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Aug 2018 10:27:16 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hellokangning.github.io/post/linux-principle-manual-programming/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This post only involves three mind maps for Linux covering principles, manual and programming. I find it is beneficial to organize my knowledge with mind map.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also realized a few captions are also useful for the full picture, so they are attached.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Refactor: Why, What, When and How</title>
      <link>https://hellokangning.github.io/post/refactor-why-what-when-how/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Aug 2018 10:45:36 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hellokangning.github.io/post/refactor-why-what-when-how/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I read &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/Refactoring-Improving-Design-Existing-Code/dp/0201485672&#34;&gt;Refactoring: Improving the Design of Existing Code&lt;/a&gt; while chasing my master degree and did not realiaze how beneficial it would be considering the number of lines I wrote.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After joining the workforce, I found its importance can never be overstressed. It is rewarding to read this book over and over, so I draw this mind map for quick index.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Binary Search for Upper Bound</title>
      <link>https://hellokangning.github.io/post/binary-search-for-upper-bound/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Aug 2018 10:55:27 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hellokangning.github.io/post/binary-search-for-upper-bound/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A frequent question I ask when interviewing some candidates is binary search. It cannot be more easier to write a binary search, but the variant may be challenging. For example, upper bound for the given target. When should I shrink my scope to left?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This post elucidates the steps of binary search by illustrating some common mistakes and sloving a problem in LeetCode. And I will remind what should be paid more attention when doing search.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Java NIO: Selector</title>
      <link>https://hellokangning.github.io/post/java-nio-selector/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jul 2018 17:54:50 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hellokangning.github.io/post/java-nio-selector/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Taking FileChannel for example in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://hellokangning.github.io/post/java-nio-channel/&#34;&gt;previous post&lt;/a&gt; may bewilder audiences: it&amp;rsquo;s non-blocking, so how does NIO achievement non-blocking? Here comes Selector.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A Selector is a Java NIO component which can examine one or more NIO Channel&amp;rsquo;s, and determine which channels are ready for reading or writing. A thread can manage multiply channels with Selector making multiple network connections feasible. This way avoids the cost of switching between threads which is expensive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is an illustration of a thread using a Selector to handle 3 Channels:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hellokangning.github.io/images/java-nio-selector-handle-channels.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Java NIO: Channel</title>
      <link>https://hellokangning.github.io/post/java-nio-channel/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jul 2018 11:00:38 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hellokangning.github.io/post/java-nio-channel/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Channels are similiar to streams available for blocking IO with a few differences:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can both read and write to Channels. Streams are typically one-way (read or write).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Channels can be read and written asynchronously.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Channels always read to, or write from, a Buffer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Channels have multiple implementations depending on the data to be read or written:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;FileChannel: Used to read and write data from and to the files&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;DatagramChannel: Used for data exchange over network using UDP packets&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SocketChannel: TCP channel to exchange data over TCP sockets&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ServerSocketChannel: An implementation similar to a web server listening to requests over a specific TCP port. It creates a new SocketChannel instance for every new connection&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This post will take FileChannel for further exploration, from example to implementation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learn Consciously</title>
      <link>https://hellokangning.github.io/post/learn-consciously/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jul 2018 17:53:35 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hellokangning.github.io/post/learn-consciously/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Learning is an eternal topic for everyone, no matter which field you are engaging in. I highly admire the guys who produce excellent performance in any specific domain. It needs patience, and hours and hours will be spent on practice. Aside from tenacity, there must be something related contributing to their success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two books changed my perspective of learning. The first one is &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/dp/B000QCQ970&#34;&gt;The Art of Learning&lt;/a&gt; telling a remarkable story of personal achievement and inspires me with a series of principles for improving performance in any field. The other, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/Learn-Better-Mastering-Business-Anything/dp/1623365260&#34;&gt;Learn Better&lt;/a&gt;, demonstrates that how we learn can matter just as much as what we learn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stimulated by my preparation for IELTS recently, I think it must be rewarding to summarize my strategy of learning, active learning or conscious learning. Most of ideas come from the above books, and I put them into practise again and again proving their effectiveness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Java NIO: Buffer</title>
      <link>https://hellokangning.github.io/post/java-nio-buffer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jul 2018 17:00:53 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hellokangning.github.io/post/java-nio-buffer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Java NIO (New IO), introduced by Java 1.4, is an alternative IO API for Java. It offers a different way of working with IO than the standard IO API&amp;rsquo;s.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Three core components of Java NIO cover:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Channels&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Buffers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Selectors&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All IO in NIO involves with Channel. Data can be read from Channel to a Buffer and vice versa.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hellokangning.github.io/images/java-nio-channel-buffer.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Buffers are used to interact with Channels. A Buffer is an allocated block of memory with fixed size, into which you can read or write data. In this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll illustrate the basic usage of Buffer and elucidate how it manages to do that from the view of source code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How HMaster Detect Death of RegionServer</title>
      <link>https://hellokangning.github.io/post/how-master-detect-death-of-regionserver/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jul 2018 10:31:19 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hellokangning.github.io/post/how-master-detect-death-of-regionserver/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Step 3 of &lt;a href=&#34;https://hellokangning.github.io/post/regionserver-stops-after-full-gc/#explanation&#34;&gt;explanation&lt;/a&gt; about what happens after Full GC may be vague. It confuses audiences by&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;ServerManager&lt;/code&gt; on &lt;code&gt;HMaster&lt;/code&gt; finds there must be something wrong with this &lt;code&gt;RegionServer&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How does &lt;code&gt;HMaster&lt;/code&gt; detect the death of &lt;code&gt;RegionServer&lt;/code&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RegionServer Stops after Full GC</title>
      <link>https://hellokangning.github.io/post/regionserver-stops-after-full-gc/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jul 2018 16:31:24 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hellokangning.github.io/post/regionserver-stops-after-full-gc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the most devastating and unpredictable latency intruders is the Java Virtual Machine’s &amp;ldquo;stop the world&amp;rdquo; pauses for garbage collection (memory clean-up). This post troubleshoots an unexpected shutdown of &lt;code&gt;RegionServer&lt;/code&gt; fundamentally caused by Full GC and makes the whole process clear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JVM Series: class File Format</title>
      <link>https://hellokangning.github.io/post/jvm-series-class-file-format/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 May 2018 16:52:29 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hellokangning.github.io/post/jvm-series-class-file-format/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today, let&amp;rsquo;s focus on the &lt;code&gt;class&lt;/code&gt; file format, the hardware- and operating system-independent binary format used to represent compiled classes and interfaces.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A &lt;code&gt;class&lt;/code&gt; file consists of a stream of 8-bit bytes. All 16-bit, 32-bit, and 64-bit quantities are constructed by reading in two, four, and eight consecutive 8-bit bytes, respectively.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JVM Series: Class Loader</title>
      <link>https://hellokangning.github.io/post/jvm-series-class-loader/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Apr 2018 18:27:20 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hellokangning.github.io/post/jvm-series-class-loader/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Java Classloader, a part of the Java Runtime Environment, dynamically loads Java classes into the Java Virtual Machine. Each Java class must be loaded by a class loader.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JVM Series: Oop and Klass</title>
      <link>https://hellokangning.github.io/post/jvm-series-oop-klass/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Apr 2018 14:46:26 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hellokangning.github.io/post/jvm-series-oop-klass/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As a part of &lt;a href=&#34;https://hellokangning.github.io/tags/jvm/&#34;&gt;JVM Series&lt;/a&gt;, this post tries to explore the object model in JVM.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IndexOutput: Lucene Index Output</title>
      <link>https://hellokangning.github.io/post/indexoutput-lucene-index-output/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Apr 2018 11:25:40 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hellokangning.github.io/post/indexoutput-lucene-index-output/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Immediately following &lt;a href=&#34;https://hellokangning.github.io/post/indexwriter-lucene-index-creation-maintenance/&#34;&gt;
Indexwriter: Lucene Index Creation and Maintenance&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;code&gt;IndexOutput&lt;/code&gt;, a random-access output stream. is used for all Lucene index output operations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IndexWriter: Lucene Index Creation and Maintenance</title>
      <link>https://hellokangning.github.io/post/indexwriter-lucene-index-creation-maintenance/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Apr 2018 14:37:02 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hellokangning.github.io/post/indexwriter-lucene-index-creation-maintenance/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;An &lt;code&gt;IndexWriter&lt;/code&gt; creates and maintains an index. It&amp;rsquo;s the basic Class defined in Lucene Core.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Troubleshooting for Threads Explosion in HBase Client</title>
      <link>https://hellokangning.github.io/post/troubleshooting-for-threads-explosion-in-hbase-client/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Mar 2018 18:27:56 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hellokangning.github.io/post/troubleshooting-for-threads-explosion-in-hbase-client/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;An issue, excessive threads of HBase client, annoyed me for a quite while. It reminds me to penetrate into uses of &lt;code&gt;Executorservice&lt;/code&gt; in HBase client. That&amp;rsquo;s the origin of this blog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Consistency Models and Protocols in Distributed System</title>
      <link>https://hellokangning.github.io/post/consistency-in-distributed-system/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Feb 2018 17:03:05 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hellokangning.github.io/post/consistency-in-distributed-system/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Data replication is a vital feature in Distrubtued System, but brings in an inevitable price to be paid: consistency mantenance. The consistency model specifies a contract between programmer and system, wherein the system guarantees that if the programmer follows the rules, memory will be consistent and the results of reading, writing, or updating memory will be predictable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Chinese, &amp;ldquo;consistency&amp;rdquo; often mixes up with &amp;ldquo;consensus&amp;rdquo; because of their similiar translations. The consensus problem requires &lt;strong&gt;agreement among a number of processes for a single data value&lt;/strong&gt;. Some of the processes may fail or be unreliable in other ways, so consensus protocols must be fault tolerant or resilient.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This post focus on consistency only, enumerating various common types of consistency models and illuminating some consistency protocols.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HBase Batch Puts with BufferedMutator</title>
      <link>https://hellokangning.github.io/post/hbase-batch-puts-with-bufferedmutator/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2018 16:56:23 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hellokangning.github.io/post/hbase-batch-puts-with-bufferedmutator/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;BufferedMutator&lt;/code&gt; is meant for batched, potentially asynchronous puts into a single table. This class relies heavily on &lt;code&gt;AsyncProcess&lt;/code&gt;, which I has explained &lt;a href=&#34;https://hellokangning.github.io/post/hbase-batch-puts-without-bufferedmutator/#asyncprocess&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. Then, we can focus on what &lt;code&gt;BufferedMutator&lt;/code&gt; does in this post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JVM Series: Overview</title>
      <link>https://hellokangning.github.io/post/jvm-series-overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2018 20:56:47 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hellokangning.github.io/post/jvm-series-overview/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When executing a java program, you may simply input in terminal, like:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-shell&#34;&gt;javac HelloWorld.java
java HelloWorld
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Behind these commands, JVM, as the cornerstone of the Java platform, does a lot of work, which are what this blog attempts to figure out. Today, a new series about JVM will be started, and this is the first episode.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HBase Batch Puts without BufferedMutator</title>
      <link>https://hellokangning.github.io/post/hbase-batch-puts-without-bufferedmutator/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2018 11:33:34 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hellokangning.github.io/post/hbase-batch-puts-without-bufferedmutator/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For batch puts, it&amp;rsquo;s better if you construct a list of puts and then call &lt;code&gt;HTable.put(final List&amp;lt;Put&amp;gt; puts)&lt;/code&gt;, because it uses a single RPC call to commit the batch, but depending on the size of the list write buffer may flush it all or not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this post, &lt;code&gt;BufferedMutator&lt;/code&gt; is excluded. It will be discussed in the near future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2017 in Review and Look Ahead</title>
      <link>https://hellokangning.github.io/post/2017-in-review-look-ahead/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2018 18:43:27 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hellokangning.github.io/post/2017-in-review-look-ahead/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After reading many blogs about retrospect of 2017, I realized that I should to do it too. it looks necessary and helpful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multiversion Concurrency Control in HBase</title>
      <link>https://hellokangning.github.io/post/multiversion-concurrency-control-in-hbase/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2017 16:19:17 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hellokangning.github.io/post/multiversion-concurrency-control-in-hbase/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Multiversion Concurrency Control (MVCC for short) manages the read/write consistency. This provides an interface for readers to determine what entries to ignore, and a mechanism for writers to obtain new write numbers, then &amp;ldquo;commit&amp;rdquo; the new writes for readers to read (thus forming atomic transactions).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Lifecycle of HBase&#39;s Put: Server-side</title>
      <link>https://hellokangning.github.io/post/a-lifecycle-of-hbase-put-server-side/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2017 15:14:28 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hellokangning.github.io/post/a-lifecycle-of-hbase-put-server-side/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Following the preceding &lt;a href=&#34;https://hellokangning.github.io/post/a-lifecycle-of-hbase-put-client-side/&#34;&gt;A Lifecycle of HBase&amp;rsquo;s Put: Client-side&lt;/a&gt;, this post will figure out how a &lt;code&gt;Put&lt;/code&gt; request does its mutation on &lt;code&gt;HRegionServer&lt;/code&gt;. The whole process involves WAL, MemStore, and Coprocessor etc. After reading this post, hope you make their roles clear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Lifecycle of HBase&#39;s Put: Client-side</title>
      <link>https://hellokangning.github.io/post/a-lifecycle-of-hbase-put-client-side/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Nov 2017 11:38:14 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hellokangning.github.io/post/a-lifecycle-of-hbase-put-client-side/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Put&lt;/code&gt; is used to perform insert or update a single row of HBase table. It&amp;rsquo;s essential to understand its lifecycle, which can be breaked into two pieces,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Client-side, How the &lt;code&gt;put&lt;/code&gt; request is built up and sent to the right &lt;code&gt;RegionServer&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Server-side, How the &lt;code&gt;RegionServer&lt;/code&gt; handle the &lt;code&gt;Put&lt;/code&gt; request and update one row.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In view of the limitation of one single post, the client-side is discussed only.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HBase Code Analysis: MemStore</title>
      <link>https://hellokangning.github.io/post/hbase-code-analysis-memstore/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Nov 2017 11:39:43 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hellokangning.github.io/post/hbase-code-analysis-memstore/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;MemStore&lt;/code&gt; holds in-memory modifications to the Store. This post deeps into the source code for sake of understanding what it really do underneath.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HBase Storage Internals</title>
      <link>https://hellokangning.github.io/post/hbase-storage-internals/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2017 11:34:49 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hellokangning.github.io/post/hbase-storage-internals/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Overview&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An HBase &lt;code&gt;Table&lt;/code&gt; consists of multiple rows.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Table will be splited into &lt;code&gt;Regions&lt;/code&gt; based on rows&amp;rsquo; lexicographical order.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A &lt;code&gt;Store&lt;/code&gt; corresponds to a column family for a table for a given region.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A Store hosts a &lt;code&gt;MemStore&lt;/code&gt; and 0 or more &lt;code&gt;StoreFiles (HFiles)&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The MemStore holds in-memory modifications to the Store.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;StoreFiles are composed of &lt;code&gt;Blocks&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fixing Elasticsearch with Red Status</title>
      <link>https://hellokangning.github.io/post/fixing-elasticsearch-with-red-status/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Oct 2017 10:05:01 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hellokangning.github.io/post/fixing-elasticsearch-with-red-status/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Elasticsearch&amp;rsquo;s red status means at least one primary shard (and all of its replicas) is missing. This reminds you of missing data: searches will return partial results, and indexing into that shard will return an exception.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding Python Decorator</title>
      <link>https://hellokangning.github.io/post/understanding-python-decorator/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Sep 2017 19:36:07 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hellokangning.github.io/post/understanding-python-decorator/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A Python decorator, similar with &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Decorator_pattern&#34;&gt;Decorator Parttern&lt;/a&gt;, is a specific change to the Python syntax that allows us to more conveniently alter functions and methods. In this post, I will try my best to deep into this advanced feature in Python.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JDK Build-in Development Tools</title>
      <link>https://hellokangning.github.io/post/jdk-build-in-development-tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Sep 2017 16:20:46 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hellokangning.github.io/post/jdk-build-in-development-tools/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The following documents contain important information you will need to know to get the most out of the JDK tools.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>*args and **kwargs Usage in Python</title>
      <link>https://hellokangning.github.io/post/args-and-kwargs-usage-in-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Sep 2017 16:46:50 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hellokangning.github.io/post/args-and-kwargs-usage-in-python/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;*args&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;**kwargs&lt;/code&gt; is a common idiom to allow arbitrary number of arguments to functions as described in the section more on &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.python.org/dev/tutorial/controlflow.html#more-on-defining-functions&#34;&gt;defining functions&lt;/a&gt; in the Python documentation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Does Client Find the Region</title>
      <link>https://hellokangning.github.io/post/how-does-client-find-the-region/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Sep 2017 11:04:57 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hellokangning.github.io/post/how-does-client-find-the-region/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;client-related source code is located in the module &lt;code&gt;hbase-client&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Directory in Lucene</title>
      <link>https://hellokangning.github.io/post/lucene-directory/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Sep 2017 16:26:31 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hellokangning.github.io/post/lucene-directory/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Directory&lt;/code&gt; represents the storage location of the indexes and generally it is a list of files. These files are called index files. Index files are normally created once and then used for read operation or can be deleted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>When finally Really Executes</title>
      <link>https://hellokangning.github.io/post/when-finally-really-executes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Sep 2017 16:22:03 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hellokangning.github.io/post/when-finally-really-executes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Epitome:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;return doesn&amp;rsquo;t really return, it pushs value to stack, then jumps to finally, which was set up by &lt;code&gt;SETUP_FINALLY&lt;/code&gt; before.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;after executing finally, &lt;code&gt;END_FINALLY&lt;/code&gt; returns.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exit Options in Python</title>
      <link>https://hellokangning.github.io/post/exit-options-in-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2017 16:47:37 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hellokangning.github.io/post/exit-options-in-python/</guid>
      <description>First candidate is os._exit, which exits without calling cleanup handlers, flushing stdio buffers, etc. (and which should normally only be used in the child process after a fork()).
Second, sys.exit is intended for use in programs. According to official document:
 This is implemented by raising the SystemExit exception, so cleanup actions specified by finally clauses of try statements are honored, and it is possible to intercept the exit attempt at an outer level.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Difference between range and xrange</title>
      <link>https://hellokangning.github.io/post/difference-between-range-and-xrange/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2017 16:22:27 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hellokangning.github.io/post/difference-between-range-and-xrange/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Short answer:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;range&lt;/code&gt; creates a list, so if you do &lt;code&gt;range(1, 10000000)&lt;/code&gt; it creates a list in memory with 9999999 elements. This will become an expensive operation on very large ranges.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;xrange&lt;/code&gt; is a sequence object that &lt;em&gt;evaluates lazily&lt;/em&gt;(it will only compute the next value when needed).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Dive into __slots__</title>
      <link>https://hellokangning.github.io/post/a-dive-into-slots/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2017 14:25:37 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hellokangning.github.io/post/a-dive-into-slots/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;__slots__&lt;/code&gt; tells interpreter not to use a dict, and only allocate space for a fixed set of attributes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Read English Books</title>
      <link>https://hellokangning.github.io/post/how-to-read-english-books/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Aug 2017 18:04:07 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hellokangning.github.io/post/how-to-read-english-books/</guid>
      <description>For the sake of learning English, I try to read the original version of The Power of Now and Hackers and Painters. To be honest, it&amp;rsquo;s very difficult, two many unacquainted words and phrases. Even only one in a sentence would affect my understanding.
Therefore, I stopped my reading and searched on the Internet for better approach to do this. After a long surfing, Here is the tips that I summarized.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Document in Lucene</title>
      <link>https://hellokangning.github.io/post/lucene-document/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Aug 2017 18:52:01 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hellokangning.github.io/post/lucene-document/</guid>
      <description>In Lucene, a Document is the unit of search and index.
 An index consists of a sequence of documents. A document contains of one or more Fields. A field is a named sequence of terms. A term is a string.  In order to index data with Lucene, you must convert it to a stream of plain-text tokens firstly. Based on the stream, the document containning fields will be created.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Guice Usage in Elasticsearch</title>
      <link>https://hellokangning.github.io/post/guice-usage-in-es/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Aug 2017 15:58:27 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hellokangning.github.io/post/guice-usage-in-es/</guid>
      <description>The motivation of using Guice lists here: Motivation.
To create bindings, extend AbstractModule and override its configure method. In the method body, call bind() to specify each binding. These methods are type checked so the compiler can report errors if you use the wrong types. Once you&amp;rsquo;ve created your modules, pass them as arguments to Guice.createInjector() to build an injector.
Elasticsearch has a ModulesBuilder which is responsible for assembling modules.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pip Install ipython Exception on EI Capitan</title>
      <link>https://hellokangning.github.io/post/pip-install-ipython-exception-on-ei-capitan/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Aug 2017 15:23:36 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hellokangning.github.io/post/pip-install-ipython-exception-on-ei-capitan/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For those impatient: OS X EI Capition shipped a security feature named System Integrity Protection, which would be a hinder for &lt;code&gt;pip&lt;/code&gt;. Try to install IPython in user mode: &lt;code&gt;pip install ipython --user&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mind Maps for Java and JVM</title>
      <link>https://hellokangning.github.io/post/java-jvm-mind-map/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jun 2017 18:14:16 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hellokangning.github.io/post/java-jvm-mind-map/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;These two mind maps are drawn for the further exploration of Java and JVM. For Java I try to cover some advanced features ranging from NIO and Thread. As to JVM, few components are covered, of course, I will replenish it at any moment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Redis Mind Map</title>
      <link>https://hellokangning.github.io/post/redis-mind-map/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Nov 2016 21:20:07 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hellokangning.github.io/post/redis-mind-map/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This post includes a few mind maps for Redis ranging from quick start to implementation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hellokangning.github.io/images/redis-quick-start.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Differences between Hashtable and HashMap</title>
      <link>https://hellokangning.github.io/post/java-hashtable-comparing-with-hashmap/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Aug 2016 12:01:40 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hellokangning.github.io/post/java-hashtable-comparing-with-hashmap/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As I mentioned before, it is vital to read code with prepared questions. Hum, How about reading code with answers? The differences between Hashtable and HashMap have been explained many times including,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;null key &amp;amp; null value&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;synchronized or not&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enumeration and Iterator&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;hash method&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am wondering how these arguments are supported by code. This post will give a view of code illustrating the above confusion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Java HashSet</title>
      <link>https://hellokangning.github.io/post/java-hashset/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2016 11:45:53 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hellokangning.github.io/post/java-hashset/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For those who has no patience to look through this post, I conclude it in a word: HashSet is backed by HashMap.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Set is a collection in which every element is unique. So does the keys in HashMap. It is reasonable to infer that the implementation of HashSet is based on HashMap, so it is. Remember &lt;a href=&#34;https://hellokangning.github.io/post/java-hashmap/#resize&#34;&gt;resize&lt;/a&gt; of HashMap? it makes no guarantees as to the iteration order of the set.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the help of HashMap, HashSet offers constant time performance for the basic operations, like &lt;code&gt;add&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;remove&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;contains&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;size&lt;/code&gt;. Iterating over this set requires time proportional to the sum of the HashSet instance&amp;rsquo;s size (the number of elements) plus the &amp;ldquo;capacity&amp;rdquo; of the backing HashMap instance (the number of buckets).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Java TreeMap</title>
      <link>https://hellokangning.github.io/post/java-treemap/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jun 2016 12:54:23 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hellokangning.github.io/post/java-treemap/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After joining the workforce, I have coded with various programming languages, like C++, Objective-C, Ruby, Python, Scala, Java, Go, etc. I ask to myself spontaneously, which language am I most skillful at? This question dismay me because I cannot answer it immediately.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since I choice to focus on Big Data, it&amp;rsquo;s pragmatic to equipped with Java and Python, two powerful weapons in this field. Reading the source code of &lt;a href=&#34;https://hellokangning.github.io/tags/java.util/&#34;&gt;java.util&lt;/a&gt; is a good start.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The leading actor of this post is &lt;code&gt;TreeMap&lt;/code&gt;, a Red-Black tree based &lt;code&gt;NavigableMap&lt;/code&gt; implementation. It has no array underneath, as many of you think. Because &lt;code&gt;TreeMap&lt;/code&gt; inherits directly &lt;code&gt;AbstractMap&lt;/code&gt;, in contrast with &lt;a href=&#34;https://hellokangning.github.io/post/java-linkedhashmap/&#34;&gt;LinkedHashMap&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Performances differ on account of distinctive data structures. This implementation provides guaranteed log(n) time cost for the &lt;code&gt;containsKey&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;get&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;put&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;remove&lt;/code&gt; operations. Now allow me to show you a close look.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Java LinkedHashMap</title>
      <link>https://hellokangning.github.io/post/java-linkedhashmap/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jun 2016 20:01:59 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hellokangning.github.io/post/java-linkedhashmap/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As its name implis, &lt;code&gt;LinkedHashMap&lt;/code&gt; is a hash table and linked list implementation of the &lt;code&gt;Map&lt;/code&gt; interface, with predictable iteration order. Different with &lt;code&gt;HashMap&lt;/code&gt;, it maintains a doubly-linked list runing through all of its entries, which also defines the iteration ordering, same as the order in which keys were inserted into the map. This order remains if a key is re-inserted into te map.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like &lt;code&gt;HashMap&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;LinkedHashMap&lt;/code&gt; provides constant-time performance for the basic operations &lt;code&gt;add&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;contains&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;remove&lt;/code&gt;, assuming the hash function disperses elements properly among the buckets.  Performance is likely to be just slightly below that of &lt;code&gt;HashMap&lt;/code&gt;, due to the added expense of maintaining the linked list,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to the linked list, this kind of map is well-suited to building LRU caches. So my questions is how &lt;code&gt;LinkedHashMap&lt;/code&gt; preserves the linked list when key changes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Java HashMap</title>
      <link>https://hellokangning.github.io/post/java-hashmap/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2016 20:42:52 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hellokangning.github.io/post/java-hashmap/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s necessary to learn with questions. Otherwise, you may distract your focus when something you don&amp;rsquo;t know appears, whether should I go deeper or not. With preliminary doubts in your mind, this would not be a problem. Learning can be direct, clear and fruitful, which brings you more sense of achievement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For this post about the source code of &lt;code&gt;HashMap&lt;/code&gt;, few questions need answers:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;data structure underneath&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;why &lt;code&gt;HashMap&lt;/code&gt; permites nulls and unsynchronized&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;does it make guarantees as to the order of the map&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;what happens when I put and get a key with value, and time complexity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;how the map shrink or expand when size changes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Java LinkedList</title>
      <link>https://hellokangning.github.io/post/java-linkedlist/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Apr 2016 11:37:29 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hellokangning.github.io/post/java-linkedlist/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;LinkedList&lt;/code&gt; is a doubly-linked list implementation of the &lt;code&gt;List&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;Deque&lt;/code&gt; interfaces. By &amp;ldquo;doubly-linked&amp;rdquo;, it means we can traverse the list from the beginning to the end, and vice versa. This class is a member of Java Collections Framework, located in &lt;code&gt;java.util&lt;/code&gt;. Let&amp;rsquo;s go straight to the source code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Java String</title>
      <link>https://hellokangning.github.io/post/java-string/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Apr 2016 11:33:34 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hellokangning.github.io/post/java-string/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;String&lt;/code&gt; is one of the most common type of data in computer languages. A Java string is a series of characters gathered together, such as &amp;ldquo;abc&amp;rdquo;. Strings are constant, which means their value cannot be changed after created.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This post introduces the basic of Java string, includes methods for examining individual characters of the sequence, for comparing strings, for searching strings, for extracting substrings and so on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>