<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Guoqing Geng</title>
    <link>https://hellokangning.github.io/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Guoqing Geng</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Powered by [Hugo](//gohugo.io). Theme by [PPOffice](http://github.com/ppoffice).</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 07 Aug 2017 18:52:01 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://hellokangning.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Document in Lucene</title>
      <link>https://hellokangning.github.io/2017/08/07/document-in-lucene/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Aug 2017 18:52:01 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hellokangning.github.io/2017/08/07/document-in-lucene/</guid>
      <description>In Lucene, a Document is the unit of search and index.
 An index consists of a sequence of documents. A document contains of one or more Fields. A field is a named sequence of terms. A term is a string.  In order to index data with Lucene, you must convert it to a stream of plain-text tokens firstly. Based on the stream, the document containning fields will be created.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Guice usage in Elasticsearch</title>
      <link>https://hellokangning.github.io/2017/08/04/guice-usage-in-elasticsearch/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Aug 2017 15:58:27 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hellokangning.github.io/2017/08/04/guice-usage-in-elasticsearch/</guid>
      <description>The motivation of using Guice lists here: Motivation.
To create bindings, extend AbstractModule and override its configure method. In the method body, call bind() to specify each binding. These methods are type checked so the compiler can report errors if you use the wrong types. Once you&amp;rsquo;ve created your modules, pass them as arguments to Guice.createInjector() to build an injector.
Elasticsearch has a ModulesBuilder which is responsible for assembling modules.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pip install ipython exception on EI Capitan</title>
      <link>https://hellokangning.github.io/2017/08/03/pip-install-ipython-exception-on-ei-capitan/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Aug 2017 15:23:36 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hellokangning.github.io/2017/08/03/pip-install-ipython-exception-on-ei-capitan/</guid>
      <description>for those impatient
OS X EI Capition shipped a security feature named System Integrity Protection, which would be a hinder for pip. Try to install IPython in user mode: pip install ipython --user.
 As a new Pythoner, I want to learn IPython spontaneously. I read the release notes carefully and found that the lastest IPython 6.0 drops Python 2.7 support. This is not a good news for me, who works on OS X EI Caption and built-in Python 2.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>